<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Clay Carson</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 15:59:39 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 15:59:39 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>November 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This newsletter is a collection of things I have found in the last month that I enjoyed, found interesting, or simply wanted to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can follow me more closely at &lt;a href=&quot;http://claycarson.net&quot; title=&quot;Personal Website&quot;&gt;my personal website&lt;/a&gt; or if you or someone you know is looking to buy or sell a home, you can point them to &lt;a href=&quot;http://claycarson.com&quot; title=&quot;Business Website &quot;&gt;my real estate website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;code-red&quot;&gt;Code Red&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://slate.com/technology/2019/10/consequential-computer-code-software-history.html&quot;&gt;The Lines of Code That Changed Everything&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To shed light on the software that has tilted the world on its axis, the editors polled computer scientists, software developers, historians, policymakers, and journalists. They were asked to pick: Which pieces of code had a huge influence? Which ones warped our lives? About 75 responded with all sorts of ideas, and Slate has selected 36. It’s not a comprehensive list—it couldn’t be, given the massive welter of influential code that’s been written. (One fave of mine that didn’t make the cut: “Quicksort”! Or maybe Ada Lovelace’s Bernoulli algorithm.) Like all lists, it’s meant to provoke thought—to help us ponder anew how code undergirds our lives and how decisions made by programmers ripple into the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some personal favorite: The Apollo 11 Lunar Module’s BAILOUT Code, The One-Line Virus, The HTML Hyperlink, The Code That Made a T-Shirt Illegal, RSS, The Lost Mars Climate Orbiter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;words-words-words&quot;&gt;Words, Words, Words&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2019/10/14/can-a-machine-learn-to-write-for-the-new-yorker?mbid=social_twitter&amp;amp;utm_brand=tny&amp;amp;utm_social-type=owned&quot;&gt;Can a Machine Learn to Write for The New Yorker?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To understand how GPT-2 writes, imagine that you’ve never learned any spelling or grammar rules, and that no one taught you what words mean. All you know is what you’ve read in eight million articles that you discovered via Reddit, on an almost infinite variety of topics (although subjects such as Miley Cyrus and the Mueller report are more familiar to you than, say, the Treaty of Versailles). You have Rain Man-like skills for remembering each and every combination of words you’ve read. Because of your predictive-text neural net, if you are given a sentence and asked to write another like it, you can do the task flawlessly without understanding anything about the rules of language. The only skill you need is being able to accurately predict the next word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;money-buys&quot;&gt;Money Buys…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://marker.medium.com/what-really-happens-when-you-become-an-overnight-millionaire-acac42990175&quot; title=&quot;What Really Happens When You Become an Overnight Millionaire?&quot;&gt;What Really Happens When You Become an Overnight Millionaire?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Peter Rahal, the 33-year-old energy bar impresario who sold RxBar to Kellogg for $600 million and became something of a consumer products legend in the process, stands in the gigantic, spotless kitchen of his new Miami Beach mansion. Behind him, floor-to-ceiling windows revealed his pool, his outdoor bar, and Sunset Harbour. Throughout the house are expensive-looking modernist metal chandeliers. The kitchen drawers are filled with gold utensils.
[…]
Rahal prides himself on struggle and says that’s how he built RxBar into a breakout success. Yet now he exists in a rich person’s wonderland, where workers appear and disappear on some imperceptible schedule to clean the pool or fix the elevator, where the kitchen’s surfaces are entirely smooth and glossy. The many contradictions now swirling in Rahal’s daily existence are not lost on him. “As life moves forward,” he says, “an easier life isn’t always a better life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;around-the-web&quot;&gt;Around The Web&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/od94zOB.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Fast Food Frequency&quot;&gt;Fast Food Frequency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A-QQ0z8yVVA&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot;&gt;F1 Steering Wheel Explained&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vole.wtf/perfect-circle/&quot;&gt;Can you draw a perfect circle?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gfycat.com/shinythisadmiralbutterfly&quot;&gt;What a stunt pilot is going through&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JR4KHfqw-oE&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot;&gt;What happens when you re-upload a YouTube video 1000 times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ds21U7coQzI&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot;&gt;How fast is a 2 hour marathon pace?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SumDHcnCRuU&amp;amp;&quot; title=&quot;Which Planet is Closest?&quot;&gt;What Planet is Closest?&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SumDHcnCRuU&amp;amp;&quot; title=&quot;Re: Which Planet is Closest?&quot;&gt;Follow up&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sign-off&quot;&gt;Sign Off&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not hesitate to reply to this months email to share links, wisdom, or thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading. Have a great month,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clay&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//newsletter/2019/11/01/Newsletter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//newsletter/2019/11/01/Newsletter.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Newsletter</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>October 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This newsletter is a collection of things I have found in the last month that I enjoyed, found interesting, or simply wanted to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can follow me more closely at &lt;a href=&quot;http://claycarson.net&quot; title=&quot;Personal Website&quot;&gt;my personal website&lt;/a&gt; or if you or someone you know is looking to buy or sell a home, you can point them to &lt;a href=&quot;http://claycarson.com&quot; title=&quot;Business Website &quot;&gt;my real estate website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-burst-bubble&quot;&gt;A Burst Bubble&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.5280.com/2019/09/the-balloon-boy-hoax-solved/&quot;&gt;The Balloon Boy Hoax—Solved!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s not difficult to piece it together: With a video camera rolling, Richard would launch the balloon and freak out. He’d call the FAA and get the balloon tracked. There’d be a tearful reunion when Falcon emerged from the basement, where he’d been told to hide. Richard would call back and say his son wasn’t in the basket. They’d make sure the Fort Collins newspaper knew about the stray saucer and the drama behind it. The story might go nationwide. With publicity in full force and a recording of every moment, networks would fight over the Heenes’ story.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Except Falcon didn’t hide where he was told to. He hid in the garage attic, not in the basement. He played with his cars and he fell asleep. The FAA said Richard needed to call 911. Deputies showed up. Neighbors began searching for Falcon. And then that silvery balloon was careening across our television screens. That’s why Mayumi’s reunion with Falcon was so believable: For a few hours, she and Richard honestly worried their son had been swept away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;chess-t-day&quot;&gt;Chess-t Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.espn.in/espn/story/_/id/27593253/why-grandmasters-magnus-carlsen-fabiano-caruana-lose-weight-playing-chess&quot;&gt;The Grandmaster Diet: How to lose weight while barely moving&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In 2004, winner Rustam Kasimdzhanov walked away from the six-game world championship having lost 17 pounds. In October 2018, Polar, a U.S.-based company that tracks heart rates, monitored chess players during a tournament and found that 21-year-old Russian grandmaster Mikhail Antipov had burned 560 calories in two hours of sitting and playing chess – or roughly what Roger Federer would burn in an hour of singles tennis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;around-the-web&quot;&gt;Around The Web&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.espn.com/espn/feature/story/_/id/27400369/the-body-issue#!&quot; title=&quot;The Body Issue - 2019&quot;&gt;The Body Issue - 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nyctimescape.com/#overview&quot; title=&quot;NYC Timescape&quot;&gt;NYC Timescape - 30 Year Time-lapse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.presentandcorrect.com/250-words-you-can-spell-with-a-calculator&quot;&gt;250 Words you can spell with a calculator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xd2TL88T9_s&quot;&gt;Can You Hear the Difference Between Cheap and Expensive Pianos?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aPb-slJH9Vs&quot;&gt;How Pencils are Made&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sign-off&quot;&gt;Sign Off&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not hesitate to reply to this months email to share links, wisdom, or thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading. Have a great month,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clay&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//newsletter/2019/10/01/Newsletter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//newsletter/2019/10/01/Newsletter.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Newsletter</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>September 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This newsletter is a collection of things I have found in the last month that I enjoyed, found interesting, or simply wanted to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can follow me more closely at &lt;a href=&quot;http://claycarson.net&quot; title=&quot;Personal Website&quot;&gt;my personal website&lt;/a&gt; or if you or someone you know is looking to buy or sell a home, you can point them to &lt;a href=&quot;http://claycarson.com&quot; title=&quot;Business Website &quot;&gt;my real estate website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-case-of-the-mondays&quot;&gt;A Case of the Monday’s&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.golf.com/news/features/2019/08/14/ryan-french-unearthing-triumphs-tragedies-monday-qualifier-life/&quot; title=&quot;Meet the man unearthing the triumphs (and tragedies) of Monday-qualifier life&quot;&gt;Meet the Man Unearthing the Triumphs (and Tragedies) of Monday-Qualifier Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every Monday the PGA Tour holds a “small” tournament to get into the week’s “big” tournament. Four spots are up for grabs and there are often over 100 vagabonding golfers trying to play their way in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I think golf is thought of as so elitist, epically pro golf — private jets and big money and handing out gloves — so I don’t think people knew this side of it existed,” French says. “They know minor-league baseball because everyone’s been to a minor-league baseball game. It’s organized. Monday qualifying is just so fractured. I don’t think people knew it existed, at least your casual golf fan didn’t. They didn’t realize there were people grinding out there sleeping in cars, and I think that’s the human interest of it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorites of French’s tweets are the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/acaseofthegolf1/status/1163104881454014466&quot;&gt;tweets&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/acaseofthegolf1/status/1152708850048471041&quot;&gt;summarize&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/acaseofthegolf1/status/1157062316871114752&quot;&gt;level&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/acaseofthegolf1/status/1162323389069111297&quot;&gt;play&lt;/a&gt; so &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/acaseofthegolf1/status/1162417675894759424&quot;&gt;simply&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;brains-are-weird&quot;&gt;Brains Are Weird&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/07/magazine/placebo-effect-medicine.html&quot; title=&quot;What if the Placebo Effect Isn’t a Trick?&quot;&gt;What if the Placebo Effect Isn’t a Trick?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And after a quarter-century of hard work, they have abundant evidence to prove it. Give people a sugar pill, they have shown, and those patients — especially if they have one of the chronic, stress-related conditions that register the strongest placebo effects and if the treatment is delivered by someone in whom they have confidence — will improve. Tell someone a normal milkshake is a diet beverage, and his gut will respond as if the drink were low fat. Take athletes to the top of the Alps, put them on exercise machines and hook them to an oxygen tank, and they will perform better than when they are breathing room air — even if room air is all that’s in the tank. Wake a patient from surgery and tell him you’ve done an arthroscopic repair, and his knee gets better even if all you did was knock him out and put a couple of incisions in his skin. Give a drug a fancy name, and it works better than if you don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;You don’t even have to deceive the patients. You can hand a patient with irritable bowel syndrome a sugar pill, identify it as such and tell her that sugar pills are known to be effective when used as placebos, and she will get better, especially if you take the time to deliver that message with warmth and close attention. Depression, back pain, chemotherapy-related malaise, migraine, post-traumatic stress disorder: The list of conditions that respond to placebos — as well as they do to drugs, with some patients — is long and growing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;screenshot-graveyard&quot;&gt;Screenshot Graveyard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.versionmuseum.com&quot;&gt;Version Museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Much like walking through a real-life museum, Version Museum aims to illustrate the visual, tangible elements of various versions of technology, rather than just the written history behind it. Wikipedia and other sites already do a fantastic job of detailing the story behind websites, apps, and everything else. This site focuses on observable changes over time. If you’re a longtime user of a certain product, there’s probably going to be some nostalgia as you look at all the previous iterations of it over the years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;around-the-web&quot;&gt;Around The Web&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hodinkee.com/packages/reference-points&quot; title=&quot;Hodinkee: Reference Points&quot;&gt;Hodinkee: Reference Points&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thereviewindex.com/us&quot;&gt;Amazon Review Summarizer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://usflags.design&quot; title=&quot;A design guide for the flags of the United States&quot;&gt;A Design Guide for the Flags of the United States&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trailsofwind.figures.cc&quot; title=&quot;The Orientation of Airport Runways&quot;&gt;The Orientation of Airport Runways&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sign-off&quot;&gt;Sign Off&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not hesitate to reply to this months email to share links, wisdom, or thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading. Have a great month,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clay&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//newsletter/2019/09/01/Newsletter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//newsletter/2019/09/01/Newsletter.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Newsletter</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>August 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This newsletter is a collection of things I have found in the last month that I enjoyed, found interesting, or simply wanted to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can follow me more closely at &lt;a href=&quot;http://claycarson.net&quot; title=&quot;Personal Website&quot;&gt;my personal website&lt;/a&gt; or if you or someone you know is looking to buy or sell a home, you can point them to &lt;a href=&quot;http://claycarson.com&quot; title=&quot;Business Website &quot;&gt;my real estate website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-crapture&quot;&gt;“The (C)Rapture”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/pooping-dark/?verso=true&quot; title=&quot;On Pooping in the Dark—No Lights, No Phones, No Distractions&quot;&gt;On Pooping in the Dark—No Lights, No Phones, No Distractions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I used to DM during every BM. Then, one afternoon a few years ago, I slipped into a poop portal. Backpacking through remote wilderness in searing heat, I felt the telltale pang. Coffee, eggs, chorizo, and water were all rushing—screamingly—to the exits. At the nearest rest stop, I dashed into a bathroom so single-mindedly I didn’t turn on the lights and collapsed onto the toilet. The immediate release, shrouded as it was in shadow, was cosmic, like waking up from a nightmare, realizing it’s Christmas, I’m 5 years old, and can fly. Though I haven’t yet been able to recreate every condition, to this day I try to dump in total darkness: no lights, no phone, the gulf between mind and body quaked shut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ring-ring&quot;&gt;Ring, Ring&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/mb88za/amazon-requires-police-to-shill-surveillance-cameras-in-secret-agreement?xyz&quot; title=&quot;Amazon Requires Police to Shill Surveillance Cameras in Secret Agreement&quot;&gt;Amazon Requires Police to Shill Surveillance Cameras in Secret Agreement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Amazon’s home security company Ring has enlisted local police departments around the country to advertise its surveillance cameras in exchange for free Ring products and a “portal” that allows police to request footage from these cameras, a secret agreement obtained by Motherboard shows. The agreement also requires police to “keep the terms of this program confidential.”
[…]
People often buy and use Ring doorbell cameras under the premise that they’re making their individual homes safer. But these people aren’t just making choices for themselves. They’re consenting to surveilling everyone in their neighborhood and anyone who comes in the vicinity of their home, including friends and family, delivery workers, and anyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;head-out-on-the-highway&quot;&gt;Head out on the Highway&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2019/07/car-crashes-arent-always-unavoidable/592447/&quot; title=&quot;Americans Shouldn’t Have to Drive, but the Law Insists on It&quot;&gt;Americans Shouldn’t Have to Drive, but the Law Insists on It&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Further entrenching automobile supremacy are laws that require landowners who build housing and office space to build housing for cars as well. In large part because of parking quotas, parking lots now cover more than a third of the land area of some U.S. cities; Houston is estimated to have 30 parking spaces for every resident. As the UCLA urban-planning professor Donald Shoup has written, this mismatch flows from legal mandates rather than market demand. Every employee who brings a car to the office essentially doubles the amount of space he takes up at work, and in urban areas his employer may be required by law to build him a $50,000 garage parking space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;around-the-web&quot;&gt;Around The Web&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/photo/2019/07/opening-day-disneyland-photos-1955/594655/&quot; title=&quot;Opening Day at Disneyland&quot;&gt;Opening Day at Disneyland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/aZV8rau.gifv&quot; title=&quot;Waste Produced by Country&quot;&gt;Waste Produced by Country&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GNZ3UCGjHo8&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot;&gt;Bushman Pranks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://history.nasa.gov/alsj/a11/A11vsMLB.gif&quot; title=&quot;Apollo 11 Landing Site vs. Baseball Field&quot;&gt;Apollo 11 Landing Site vs. Baseball Field&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;book-em&quot;&gt;Book ‘Em&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;golf-architecture-economy-in-course-construction-and-green-keeping&quot;&gt;Golf Architecture: Economy in Course Construction and Green-Keeping&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A good golf course is a great asset to the nation. Those who harangue against land being diverted from agriculture and used for golf have little sense of proportion. Comparing the small amount of land utilised for golf with the large amount devoted to agriculture, we get infinitely more value out of the former than the latter. We all eat too much. During the Great War the majority were all the fitter for being rationed and getting a smaller amount of food, but none of us get enough fresh air, pleasurable excitement, and exercise. Health and happiness are everything in this world.
&lt;em&gt;- Dr. Alister MacKenzie&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get a copy &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Golf-Architecture-Economy-Construction-Green-Keeping/dp/1733591141&quot; title=&quot;Golf Architecture: Economy in Course Construction and Green-Keeping&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Cost: $3, 1 hour - easily a worthwhile exchange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sign-off&quot;&gt;Sign Off&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not hesitate to reply to this months email to share links, wisdom, or thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading. Have a great month,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clay&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//newsletter/2019/08/01/Newsletter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//newsletter/2019/08/01/Newsletter.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Newsletter</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>July 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This newsletter is a collection of things I have found in the last month that I enjoyed, found interesting, or simply wanted to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can follow me more closely at &lt;a href=&quot;http://claycarson.net&quot; title=&quot;Personal Website&quot;&gt;my personal website&lt;/a&gt; or if you or someone you know is looking to buy or sell a home, you can point them to &lt;a href=&quot;http://claycarson.com&quot; title=&quot;Business Website &quot;&gt;my real estate website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;Ow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.themarshallproject.org/2019/06/07/the-underground-art-of-prison-tattoos&quot;&gt;The Underground Art of Prison Tattoos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Prisoners take apart beard trimmers or CD players to get at the tiny motor, which they can adapt to make the tattoo needle go up and down quickly enough.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The needle itself is often made from a metal guitar string split in two by holding it over an open flame until it snaps in half, creating a fine point. The springs inside gel pens can also flatten into needles.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;One former prisoner who now runs a tattoo shop said he used to make black ink by trapping soot in a milk carton placed over a burning pile of plastic razors or Bible pages. He would mix the leftover ash and soot with a bit of alcohol (for hygienic purposes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;go-no-go&quot;&gt;Go, No Go&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://apolloinrealtime.org/11/&quot;&gt;Apollo 11 in Real Time&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This website replays the Apollo 11 mission as it happened, 50 years ago. It consists entirely of historical material, all timed to Ground Elapsed Time–the master mission clock. Footage of Mission Control, film shot by the astronauts, and television broadcasts transmitted from space and the surface of the Moon, have been painstakingly placed to the very moments they were shot during the mission, as has every photograph taken, and every word spoken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BHIo6qwJarI&quot;&gt;Public Service Broadcasting - Go!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pitch-perfect&quot;&gt;Pitch Perfect&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ljrich.wordpress.com/2014/04/29/living-with-perfect-pitch-what-its-really-like/&quot;&gt;Living with Perfect Pitch and Synaesthesia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;That car horn beeps an F major chord, this kettle’s in A flat, some bedside lights get thrown out because they are out of tune with other appliances…bath taps squeak in E, this person sneezes in E flat. That printer’s in D mostly. The microwave is in the same key as the washing machine.
[…]
When I taste things, I also hear music, mainly chords – sugar and desserts almost always in major key and chocolate and coffee are particularly complex sounds, with overtones and harmonics. I love broccoli and cauliflower which are a cycle of fifths. Sushi tastes like power chords on an acoustic guitar. Lemon meringue pie is a concoction of A major chords and inversions, 7ths and minors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;around-the-web&quot;&gt;Around The Web&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/theDIYSRC/videos&quot;&gt;Rescue and Restore - Toy Restoration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.animatedknots.com/&quot;&gt;Animated Knots Tying&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mobile.twitter.com/shistorians/status/1140439277991530499&quot; title=&quot;Pebble Beach in 1929&quot;&gt;Pebble Beach in 1929&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sign-off&quot;&gt;Sign Off&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not hesitate to reply to this months email to share links, wisdom, or thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading. Have a great month,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clay&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//newsletter/2019/07/01/Newsletter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//newsletter/2019/07/01/Newsletter.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Newsletter</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>June 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This newsletter is a collection of things I have found in the last month that I enjoyed, found interesting, or simply wanted to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can follow me more closely at &lt;a href=&quot;http://claycarson.net&quot; title=&quot;Personal Website&quot;&gt;my personal website&lt;/a&gt; or if you or someone you know is looking to buy or sell a home, you can point them to &lt;a href=&quot;http://claycarson.com&quot; title=&quot;Business Website &quot;&gt;my real estate website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bob-why-a-pdf&quot;&gt;Bob, Why a PDF?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pdfa.org/a-technical-and-cultural-assessment-of-the-mueller-report-pdf/&quot; title=&quot;A Technical and Cultural Assessment of the Mueller Report PDF&quot;&gt;A Technical and Cultural Assessment of the Mueller Report PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Everyone knew that the US Department of Justice and Attorney General Barr would release the Mueller Report as a PDF file.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In fact, it’s safe to say that AG Barr never considered delivering anything else. No one would have even suggested a Word file, or a set of TIFF images, or a website, or an XPS file, or EPUB, or plain text. It’s 2019, but it seems safe to say that they simply assumed they’d use PDF.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If you are like most people, you simply assumed it would be a PDF as well.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-lows-of-colonials-2019-champion&quot;&gt;The Lows of Colonial’s 2019 Champion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.golf.com/tour-and-news/complicated-kevin-na-case-study-frailty-golfers-psyche&quot; title=&quot;The Complicated Kevin Na: A Case Study in the Frailty of a Golfer’s Psyche&quot;&gt;The Complicated Kevin Na: A Case Study in the Frailty of a Golfer’s Psyche&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;On every swing a battle raged between his technical proficiency and mental fragility. He would stand over the ball, his mind jumbled with swing thoughts. His hands strangled the grip, his arms were knots of tension. The seconds would tick by, and he felt powerless to lift the club. Then the uncertainty would ebb just long enough to allow him to start his swing, and the resulting shot would be flawless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously painful to watch: “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oRKH4nIWRUg&quot; title=&quot;Pull the Trigger!&quot;&gt;Pull the trigger!&lt;/a&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;around-the-web&quot;&gt;Around The Web&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://507movements.com/index01.html&quot; title=&quot;Five Hundred and Seven Mechanical Movements&quot;&gt;Five Hundred and Seven Mechanical Movements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://reaganray.com/2019/05/20/airline-logos.html&quot; title=&quot;Airline Logos&quot;&gt;Classic Airline Logos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://flipflopflyin.com/flipflopflyball/info-foullines.html&quot;&gt;The Foul Lines of Major League Baseball&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://flipflopflyin.com/flipflopflyball/infographics.html&quot; title=&quot;Baseball Infographics&quot;&gt;And Dozen’s More Baseball Infographics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dirtycarart.com/grime-scene/#&quot; title=&quot;Dirty Car Art&quot;&gt;Dirty Car Art&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sign-off&quot;&gt;Sign Off&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not hesitate to reply to this months email to share links, wisdom, or thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading. Have a great month,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clay&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//newsletter/2019/06/01/Newsletter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//newsletter/2019/06/01/Newsletter.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Newsletter</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>May 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This newsletter is a collection of things I have found in the last month that I enjoyed, found interesting, or simply wanted to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can follow me more closely at &lt;a href=&quot;http://claycarson.net&quot; title=&quot;Personal Website&quot;&gt;my personal website&lt;/a&gt; or if you or someone you know is looking to buy or sell a home, you can point them to &lt;a href=&quot;http://claycarson.com&quot; title=&quot;Business Website &quot;&gt;my real estate website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lego-tower&quot;&gt;Lego Tower&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scribd.com/document/66096946/A-Redditor-s-Dilemma&quot; title=&quot;Analysis: How many stacked Lego’s would it take to destroy the bottom Lego&quot;&gt;Analysis: How many stacked Lego’s would it take to destroy the bottom Lego&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t understand any of this analysis so I’ll spoil it; It would take 454,159 Legos stacked one on top of the other to destroy the bottom brick. That is 2.7 miles of Legos…halfway up Everest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sunday-red&quot;&gt;Sunday Red&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://joeposnanski.com/tiger-and-time/&quot;&gt;Tiger and Time&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the unique perspective of Golden Bell:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And the roars for him were unlike those even for Arnie and Jack. I think that’s because Tiger wasn’t adored like Arnie, and he wasn’t lionized like Jack. No there was something else about him, something more aspirational. I am not sure I can describe it — I am no poet, I am the subject of poetry — but as I understand it, Tiger offered to take the crowd to a place where golf had never gone. He was an astronaut. He hit shots no one had ever hit. He saw possibilities where others saw tree branches and double bogeys. He brought order to a disorderly game.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Anyway, that’s how I have heard it described.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Then, one day, something with Tiger Woods changed. One hears things, but I am not one to partake in rumors. But I could see that Tiger no longer commanded the game the way he had. The crowds still shouted for him, but their cheers were less confident and more nervous. He grew older. He seemed to have a different swing every time I saw him. And then, some years, he did not show up at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;strike-three&quot;&gt;Strike Three&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bu.edu/today/2019/mlb-umpires-strike-zone-accuracy/&quot; title=&quot;Time for Robo-umps?&quot;&gt;Time for Robo-umps?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This human element of the game adds color but it comes at a high cost: too many mistakes. In 2018, MLB umpires, made 34,294 incorrect ball and strike calls for an average of 14 per game or 1.6 per inning. Many umpires well exceeded this number. Some of these flubbed calls were game changing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;around-the-web&quot;&gt;Around The Web&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.redd.it/09zt0whwl1q21.gif&quot; title=&quot;Hours of Daylight&quot;&gt;Hours of Daylight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://preview.redd.it/od94t7ohh9q21.gif?format=mp4&amp;amp;s=9c4cccbf85fcc92a920cf12faf35c0713a071e1f&quot; title=&quot;Angle of the Sun&quot;&gt;Angle of the Sun&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l-wUKu_V2Lk&quot; title=&quot;How Animators Created the Spider-Verse&quot;&gt;How Animators Created the Spider-Verse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quickdraw.withgoogle.com&quot; title=&quot;Quick Draw with Google&quot;&gt;Quick Draw with Google&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://reprage.com/post/how-banksy-authenticates-his-work&quot; title=&quot;How Banksy Authenticates His Work&quot;&gt;How Banksy Authenticates His Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sign-off&quot;&gt;Sign Off&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not hesitate to reply to this months email to share links, wisdom, or thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading. Have a great month,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clay&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//newsletter/2019/05/01/Newsletter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//newsletter/2019/05/01/Newsletter.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Newsletter</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>April 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This newsletter is a collection of things I have found in the last month that I enjoyed, found interesting, or simply wanted to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can follow me more closely at &lt;a href=&quot;http://claycarson.net&quot; title=&quot;Personal Website&quot;&gt;my personal website&lt;/a&gt; or if you or someone you know is looking to buy or sell a home, you can point them to &lt;a href=&quot;http://claycarson.com&quot; title=&quot;Business Website &quot;&gt;my real estate website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;m68&quot;&gt;M68&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/19/18263844/apple-iphone-prototype-m68-original-development-board-red&quot;&gt;An Exclusive Look at an Original iPhone Prototype&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Apple had developed the iPhone in secret over those two and a half years, and for many inside the company, the device had only been known by the codenames “M68” and “Purple 2.” Apple was focused on surprising everyone with the iPhone, and that meant that many of the engineers working on the original handset didn’t even know what it would eventually look like.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;To achieve that level of secrecy, Apple created special prototype development boards that contained nearly all of the iPhone’s parts, spread out across a large circuit board. The Verge has obtained exclusive access to the original iPhone M68 prototype board from 2006 / 2007, thanks to Red M Sixty, a source that asked to remain anonymous. It’s the first time this board has been pictured publicly, and it provides a rare historical look at an important part of computing history, showing how Apple developed the original iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;80658175170943878571660636856403766975289505440883277824000000000000&quot;&gt;80658175170943878571660636856403766975289505440883277824000000000000&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://czep.net/weblog/52cards.html&quot;&gt;52 Cards Shuffled&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summarized:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Set a timer to count down 52! seconds (that’s 8.0658x1067 seconds).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Stand on the equator, and take a step forward every billion years.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When you’ve circled the earth once, take a drop of water from the Pacific Ocean, and repeat.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When the Pacific Ocean is empty, lay a sheet of paper down, refill the ocean and carry on.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When your stack of paper reaches the sun, take a look at the timer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 3 left-most digits won’t have changed. 8.063x1067 seconds left to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Repeat the whole process 1000 times to get 1/3 of the way through that time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5.385x1067 seconds left to go. To kill that time you try something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Shuffle a deck of cards, deal yourself 5 card poker hand every billion years.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Each time you get a royal flush, buy a lottery ticket.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Each time that ticket wins the jackpot, throw a grain of sand in the grand canyon&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When the grand canyon’s full, take 1oz of rock off Mount Everest. Empty the canyon and start over again.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When Everest has been leveled, check the timer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s barely any change. 5.364x1067 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The timer would run out sometime during your 255th time through the process.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;feeding-the-algorithm&quot;&gt;Feeding the Algorithm&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-internet-knows-you-better-than-your-spouse-does/&quot;&gt;The Internet Knows You Better Than Your Spouse Does&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Then the investigators had the program examine the likes of other Facebook users. If the software had as few as 10 [likes] for analysis, it was able to evaluate that person about as well as a co-worker did. Given 70 likes, the algorithm was about as accurate as a friend. With 300 [likes], it was more successful than the person’s spouse. Even more astonishing to the researchers, feeding likes into their program enabled them to predict whether someone suffered from depression or took drugs and even to infer what the individual studied in school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;around-the-web&quot;&gt;Around The Web&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brettterpstra.com/2019/03/07/the-ultimate-guide-to-duckduckgo/&quot; title=&quot;The Ultimate Guide to DuckDuckGo&quot;&gt;The Ultimate Guide to DuckDuckGo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/03/10/technology/internet-cables-oceans.html?smid=nytcore-ios-share&quot; title=&quot;‘People think that data is in the
  cloud, but it’s not. It’s in the ocean.’&quot;&gt;Data is in the Ocean, Not the Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.everysecond.io&quot; title=&quot;Every Second&quot;&gt;Every Second&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sign-off&quot;&gt;Sign Off&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not hesitate to reply to this months email to share links, wisdom, or thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading. Have a great month,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clay&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//newsletter/2019/04/01/Newsletter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//newsletter/2019/04/01/Newsletter.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Newsletter</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>March 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This newsletter is a collection of things I have found in the last month that I enjoyed, found interesting, or simply wanted to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can follow me more closely at &lt;a href=&quot;http://claycarson.net&quot; title=&quot;Personal Website&quot;&gt;my personal website&lt;/a&gt; or if you or someone you know is looking to buy or sell a home, you can point them to &lt;a href=&quot;http://claycarson.com&quot; title=&quot;Business Website &quot;&gt;my real estate website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;aberdeen-air&quot;&gt;Aberdeen Air&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://spark.adobe.com/page/Hf608dyPNOsVY/&quot; title=&quot;The World’s Busiest Commercial Heliport&quot;&gt;The World’s Busiest Commercial Heliport&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Aberdeen’s area of responsibility over the North Sea is the same size as the entire UK landmass, approximately 100,000² nautical miles. Most of this area is ‘uncontrolled’ Class G airspace, with a number of military Danger Areas; this makes the controlling environment complex and demanding.
[…]
Tricky conditions such as strong winds, fog in summer and snow in winter provide challenges to the team in Aberdeen, with high waves around the rigs and a phenomenon called ‘triggered lightning’ (where the movement of rotor blade generates electricity between them in certain weather conditions) also affect operations, making it one of the most challenging and interested places to be an air traffic controller anywhere in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;neighborhood-golf-association-from-heller-films-on-vimeo&quot;&gt;Neighborhood Golf Association from HELLER films on Vimeo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/317860394&quot;&gt;Neighborhood Golf Association&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For the past 10 years, street photographer Patrick Barr aka Tiger Hood has become a local legend known for bringing golf to the streets of NYC. It’s a game that requires only three items: a golf club, a newspaper-stuffed milk carton, and a crate. What was initially just a way for Barr to pass time has gained traction from major news outlets and celebrities on a global scale. However, street golf seems to overshadow his true passion… photography. Barr’s archive consists of thousands of mind blowing film photographs of NYC from the 1990’s to 2000’s. His goal was to preserve a time and place that he predicted would dissolve in the coming years. With his archive as evidence, he predicted correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;around-the-web&quot;&gt;Around The Web&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLibNZv5Zd0dweG40QXqhvOk-L1XymbfXi&quot; title=&quot;Wired: Almost Impossible&quot;&gt;Wired: Almost Impossible&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://darksitefinder.com/maps/world.html#4/39.20/-99.67&quot; title=&quot;Dark Site Finder&quot;&gt;Dark Site Finder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7Q9VyHJ1l2Q&quot; title=&quot;Cell --&amp;gt; Tadpole&quot;&gt;Cell —&amp;gt; Tadpole&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLS_gQd8UB-hLbR-ustuOtdgZ1U1y8037a&quot; title=&quot;Creating Saturday Night Live&quot;&gt;Creating Saturday Night Live&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.barelymaps.com/&quot; title=&quot;Barely Maps&quot;&gt;Barely Maps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sign-off&quot;&gt;Sign Off&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not hesitate to reply to this months email to share links, wisdom, or thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading. Have a great month,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clay&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//newsletter/2019/03/01/Newsletter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//newsletter/2019/03/01/Newsletter.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Newsletter</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>February 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This newsletter is a collection of things I have found in the last month that I enjoyed, found interesting, or simply wanted to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can follow me more closely at &lt;a href=&quot;http://claycarson.net&quot; title=&quot;Personal Website&quot;&gt;my personal website&lt;/a&gt; or if you or someone you know is looking to buy or sell a home, you can point them to &lt;a href=&quot;http://claycarson.com&quot; title=&quot;Business Website &quot;&gt;my real estate website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;is-my-brain-intact&quot;&gt;“Is my brain intact?”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nautil.us/issue/61/coordinates/the-strange-brain-of-the-worlds-greatest-solo-climber-rp&quot; title=&quot;The Strange Brain of the World’s Greatest Solo Climber&quot;&gt;The Strange Brain of the World’s Greatest Solo Climber&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Honnold is twice as sensation-seeking as the average person, and fully 20 percent higher than the average high sensation seeker. The most likely explanation for his flatline amygdala activation in the scanner, Joseph says, is that the tasks she set for him simply were not strong enough tea.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Honnold also scores as exceedingly conscientious, associated with the ability to concentrate, remain focused on a task, and see things through. He also surveyed high in premeditation, his typical modus operandi, and very low in neuroticism, making him unlikely to ruminate over unlikely outcomes or risks that are impossible to manage. “If you don’t have any fear to begin with,” Honnold says, “there’s a lot less to control.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“He has the traits that enable him to be incredibly focused, and incredibly patient, but at the same time totally sensation seeking,” Joseph says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honnald’s most acclaimed climb is being the first free solo (climb without ropes) El Capitan. The documentary featuring this achievement, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationalgeographic.com/films/free-solo/&quot; title=&quot;Free Solo&quot;&gt;Free Solo&lt;/a&gt;, was recently nominated for an Oscar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The movie is a 97 minute stress test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;putt-putt&quot;&gt;Putt-Putt&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thesandtrap.com/forums/topic/93352-putting-with-the-flagstick-in/&quot; title=&quot;Putting with the Flagstick In&quot;&gt;Analysis: Putting with the Flagstick In&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usga.org/content/usga/home-page/rules-hub/rules-modernization/major-changes/major-changes.html&quot; title=&quot;USGA's 2019 Rule Changes&quot;&gt;USGA’s 2019 Rule changes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usga.org/content/usga/home-page/rules-hub/rules-modernization/major-changes/ball-played-from-the-putting-green-hits-unattended-flagstick-in-hole.html&quot; title=&quot;There is no longer a penalty if a ball played from the putting green hits a flagstick left in the hole&quot;&gt;there is no longer a penalty if a ball played from the putting green hits a flagstick left in the hole&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TLDR; You should leave the flagstick in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The flagstick slows the ball by a greater factor than it decreases the time the ball spends suspended over the hole.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Unless you have exceptional distance control, effective capture speed can remain about the same.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Hitting the ball more firmly allows for a larger margin of error. It also reduces the tendency of a slow-moving putt to “wobble” or be moved off-line due to imperfections.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Players, particularly poorer putters, leave a lot of putts from 6’ to 15’ short. This change would let them be more aggressive.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The situations where the flagstick should be removed (it leans too much, it’s moving around a lot in the wind) almost never occur.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The flagstick offers an aid - it gives the player yet another point or two at which to aim.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bryson DeChambeau, the most scientific player on tour (at least boastfully), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.golfdigest.com/story/bryson-dechambeau-says-hell-putt-with-the-pin-in-next-year-most-of-the-time-because-science&quot; title=&quot;says&quot;&gt;says&lt;/a&gt; that he will almost always leave the flagstick in because of the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coefficient_of_restitution&quot; title=&quot;Coefficient of Restitution&quot;&gt;coefficient of restitution&lt;/a&gt;”. Good to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cable-guy&quot;&gt;“Cable Guy!”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.huffingtonpost.com/entry/cable-tech-dick-cheney-sex-dungeon_us_5c0ea571e4b06484c9fd4c21&quot; title=&quot;I Was A Cable Guy. I Saw The Worst Of America.&quot;&gt;I Was A Cable Guy. I Saw The Worst Of America.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I can’t tell you about a specific day as a cable tech. I can’t tell you my first customer was a cat hoarder. I can tell you the details, sure. That I smeared Vicks on my lip to try to cover the stench of rugs and walls and upholstery soaked in cat piss. That I wore booties, not to protect the carpets from the mud on my boots but to keep the cat piss off my soles. I can tell you the problem with her cable service was that her cats chewed through the wiring. That I had to move a mummified cat behind the television to replace the jumper. That ammonia seeped into the polyester fibers of my itchy blue uniform, clung to the sweat in my hair. That the smell stuck to me through the next job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;around-the-web&quot;&gt;Around The Web&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/baseball/comments/ac6foj/oc_the_most_meaningless_game_of_2018/&quot; title=&quot;Analysis: The Most Meaningless Game of Baseball in 2018&quot;&gt;The Most Meaningless Game of Major League Baseball in 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IrabKK9Bhds&quot; title=&quot;They Shall Not Grow Old&quot;&gt;Peter Jackson’s They Shall Not Grow Old&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://adventuresinmapping.com/2019/01/10/inverted-grand-canyon/&quot; title=&quot;Inverted Grand Canyon&quot;&gt;Inverted Grand Canyon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/HalfEatenScone/status/1084855992154640388&quot;&gt;G-y-l-l-e-n-h-a-a-l&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WJqg3B2_Kwc&quot; title=&quot;The Speed of Light on Earth&quot;&gt;The Speed of Light on Earth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sign-off&quot;&gt;Sign Off&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not hesitate to reply to this months email to share links, wisdom, or thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading. Have a great month,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clay&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//newsletter/2019/02/01/Newsletter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//newsletter/2019/02/01/Newsletter.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Newsletter</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
